Welcome to the complete web developer boot camp My name is Angela.
I'm a senior developer and the lead instructor be out for FREE.
London's highest rated programming Bootcamp to date a top over 120000 students in person and online.
I'm so excited that I now have the privilege of being your instructor for this course in the coming
lesson.
You can look forward to the same curriculum as our in-person programming bootcamp.
So it doesn't matter if you've never programmed before.
Because I'm going to start at the beginning and I'll take you step by step so that you understand every
single line of code that we write together we'll be covering some of the latest tools and technology
including HELOC access javascript longer D-B express Jasp and a whole lot more.
As a student on this course you're going to be saving yourself a lot of time because instead of having
to deal with outdated or incomprehensible tutorials you now get access to a fully uptodate curriculum
which is going to take you from beginner to mastery.
You're also going to be saving yourself a lot of money because instead of having to take time off work
or spend tens of thousands of dollars on an in-person programming bootcamp You'll get access to exactly
the same content when you get to do it in your own time and on your own terms for a fraction of the
price.
By the end of the course you will be fluently programming by yourself and along the way you will have
built over 16 fully fledged Web sites and a web application ready to take on a job as a professional
developer or to build your next tech startup.
One of my greatest passions in life is understanding how human blood.
Ive spent years researching programming education and applying what I found in designing bootcamp curriculum.
I have some of the highest rated development courses across the web but don't just take my word for
it check out my past students at the same.
This is the most comprehensive and most up to date course on full stock web development.
There are new modules being added constantly to make sure that you are always up to date with the latest
technology.
I was a student on this course.
You now have access to everything you need to learn to code and become a web developer.
So what are you still waiting for.
Join me on the next lesson and let's get started.