So now that we've spoken about how the Internet works in this episode I want to talk about how exactly
do Web site work.
What exactly does a TMLC SS and Javascript do exactly.
Now in order to access a web page we all know that you need a browser right and that can be Chrome Safari
Firefox whatever is your favorite one.
These are all pieces of software that allow you to look up the IP address of your web site and be able
to receive data that it can render into these beautiful Web sites that we see now the data that you
receive from the server usually consists of three types of files.
H TMLC SS and Javascript.
And it's very likely that you would have come across these types of files or these words before because
they're so common and they're so integral to how web sites work.
But what exactly do they do and why are there so many different types of files.
Why can't we just have one file that's you know a Web site.
Well they actually have very different jobs.
The m code file is responsible for the structure of your web site.
So if a Web site was a house then the h him l would be the builder who would come in to build the walls
or put in a toilet.
Basically they establish the structure of your house and when you write HMO code you also build up the
structure of your website so you could use the amount add an image or button or text box whatever it
is that you need in your website.
Now the second type of file or CSSA files and these files are responsible for styling your Web site.
So if you are building a house then this would be the painters and decorators they would be going around
painting the walls or adding stylistic flourishes to your place and generally making the place look
the way that you want it to.
And that's exactly what CSSA code does as well.
When you incorporate CSSA it allows you to specify how you want your Web site to look.
So you could say that yes I have a button that I got from my age to mail but that button I want it to
be red and I want the text to be white and I want the font of the tax to be an aerial that is all done
using CSSA code.
Now the final component is the javascript code and this is the code that allows your Web site to actually
do things or have behavior.
And if you are building a house you would have the electrician come in who would be able to connect
the wires so that your lightbulbs actually switch on or somebody who comes in and does the plumbing
so that your toilet can actually flush and the javascript code does exactly that.
It allows your Web site to actually do things and have behavior.
So for example that person I added earlier on with my age HTML code only when I have the javascript
code can I actually make it do something interesting like send off an email.
So if we take the Google web site as an example again once we receive these files from Google server
when our browser loads up the ASTM l files will get to see the structure of the Web site.
Namely there's one image which has their logo.
There's two buttons and there's a text box where we can enter our search.
Now when we receive the CSSA files then that will modify the appearance of all of those components.
We don't have any more buttons or any more images but they now look the way that Google wanted it to.
And finally when we incorporate the javascript files then our website actually starts having behavior
has functionality and is actually able to do something rather than just display some images and text
to us.
Now with the knowledge that we've already acquired we can already start messing around with web sites
on the Internet.
So open up chrome and head over to tech crunch dot com.
And if you're not familiar with it it's basically a technology news Web site where I get my latest tech
news.
Now once you're over here I want you to right click on the title here and click on inspect.
Now this brings up the chrome developer tools and we're going to be exploring this in a lot more detail.
But for now we're going to use it to do something really simple.
You can see that when I right click on that heading and click inspect it automatically opens up the
entire code file that was used to render this website.
So these are all of the elements that make up this Web site.
And when you click on inspect it will highlight to you the part of the code that corresponds to the
thing that you right clicked right.
In this case it's this title.
And inside this title you can see that there is a link which means that when you click on it.
It'll go to another web page but it's also got a bit of text.
So right inside chrome developer tools if you double click on the bit of text that corresponds to the
title you can actually edit it.
So let's go ahead and change the front page of tech crunch.
Let's say something like
So this is a great way of pranking your friends especially when they can see that you're on Tech Crunch
dotcom.
And the title of any of the text on the Web site is what you wanted to say and this is a great joke
to play on friends who are maybe not quite as technologically advanced as you because they haven't taken
the course that you have now unfortunately.
When I hit refresh on this Web site all of my good work is gone.
And the reason is because when I'm editing it here inside my browser I'm actually changing the local
copy of this file that I got back from the Google servers but when I click refresh then that makes a
new request to the Google servers to load up a fresh copy of the Web site.
So of course then an update to the original content but in the coming lessons we're going to be working
with HMO CSSA and Javascript so that you can create and host live on the internet your very own Web
sites and through learning how to code and how to build web sites you're going to be able to make websites
that say anything that you wanted to look the way that you wanted to and have the functionality that
you need.
So all of that and more.
I'll see you on the next lesson.